Welcome to What is Cloud Security Part 2.
Organizations are migrating their workload to a hybrid cloud environment increasing the
threat attack surface.
This expansion can result in new data security and compliance challenges.
Thus, you require a robust data-centric cybersecurity program to protect your data.
In addition, you require centralized visibility and monitoring against unauthorized access,
exposure, or data theft across your enterprise data environment.
Let’s discuss some data security capabilities that you can implement to protect your data.
To secure data, you can improve maturity across people, process, and technology.
Identify your most critical data assets, who has access to them, and how they are protected.
You can prevent data loss by detecting, preventing, and enforcing policy violations to avoid accidental
data loss.
Implement data security governance by establishing process, metrics, and continuous steady-state
data discovery and classification.
In addition, it is critical to monitor database security by enforcing data protection and
compliance policies across hybrid cloud environments.
Your next focus in a cloud environment should be the management of access controls and authentication.
You need to develop Cloud identity and access management (IAM) strategies that provide and
work on zero trust architecture, risk protection, and constantly authenticate any user to any
resource.
An organization should consider the following points while building the IBM cloud:
Modernize at your own pace, matching your business requirements.
Retain your existing investments and on-premises applications, while slowly inducting the right
cloud IAM architecture to complement or replace your framework.
Establish a zero-trust implementation that will provide a centralized access control,
preserve client confidentiality, reduce insider threats, and secure your remote resources.
Zero trust model and plan use an environment that securely connects the right users to
the right data at the right time under the right conditions, while also protecting your
organization from cyber threats.
Enable scalability for your cloud IAM for millions of users or transactions without
a major modification of the infrastructure.
Another element of cloud security is cloud network security which refers to the security
measures, technology, policies, controls, and processes used to protect data on public,
private, and hybrid cloud networks.
There are many security implications when you extend your network to a cloud environment.
To meet modern network security requirements, organizations need to deploy and manage network
security built directly on the cloud.
The benefits of cloud network security are: Centralized security monitoring and management
Easy management and updating of granular policies Real-time detection and powerful prevention
against intrusions, DDoS, and other web-based attacks
Automated configuration and management, helping to eliminate misconfiguration errors, and
maintain control over traffic Encryption services to protect data at rest
and in transit Centralized protection and management of identity
and access Let’s summarize the best practices you can
follow for cloud security.
There are some critical steps under three phases that you can follow.
First is identifying your cloud usage state and risks.
Second is protecting your cloud system, and third is responding to attacks.
The first phase comprises: Identifying how your data is accessed
Detecting unknown cloud usage Checking your configurations for cloud services
Monitoring for signs of malicious usage of cloud data
In the second phase, you can protect your cloud system by:
Assigning protection policies Encrypting sensitive data
Formulating policies for data sharing Restricting data sharing to unknown devices
Implementing a bot protection and mitigation solution
Using a proper anti-malware solution The third phase offers best practices for
responding to attacks and attempts to attack: Add additional authentication and verification
steps for high-risk access scenarios Add new policies for new cloud services
The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) has made a list of best practices and
principles that establish a secure and sustainable cloud computing framework.
These principles are NIST's five pillars of a cybersecurity framework: Identify, Protect,
Detect, Respond, and Recover.
Another emerging technology in cloud security that supports cybersecurity framework is cloud
security posture management (CSPM).
CSPM solutions are designed to address a common error in many cloud environments, that is,
misconfigurations.
CPSM also addresses issues by helping in the deployment of the core components of cloud
security.
They include identity and access management (IAM), regulatory compliance management, traffic
monitoring, threat response, risk mitigation, and digital asset management.
The colossal increase in cloud adoption across the cyberworld will motivate cybercriminals
to target organizations in the cloud environment.
Although organizations are taking adequate security measures, they are still vulnerable
to cyber-attacks.
The current major trend in cloud security includes multi-cloud strategies such as cybersecurity
mesh, zero-trust security models, hybrid and multi-cloud environment, cloud-native tools
and applications, deployment of DevSecOps, securing remote workforces, and AI and machine
learning for threat detection.
The focus is on privacy and data protection regulations.